A Guide to the Davison Fund, Inc. records, Treasurer (I). FA064
Rockefeller Archive Center
Davison Fund, Inc. records, Treasurer (I)
1934-1942
Rockefeller Archive Center
Davison Fund
FA064
6 Cubic Feet 3 document cases, 9 ledger volumes
Scope and Contents
Davison Fund I records were kept by the Fund's treasurer and include minutes of trustee and committee meetings and financial materials.
Biographical / Historical
The Davison Fund, Inc. was established by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. having in mind the charitable undertakings which had formerly received his personal consideration. The establishment contained no instruction as to beneficiaries, nor any limitation as to field. The beneficiaries selected by the Fund were regarded as a means to an end, the effective application of resources for charitable purposes. In general, the program developed from two motivations: an interest in the social, cultural, educational and health aspects of the citizens of New York City and its environs (including Westchester County); and, "the recognition of the outstanding importance and wide significance of certain problems which cut across national and international boundaries and which invite the cooperation and support of thoughtful men everywhere."
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Related Materials
See also the Davison Fund, Inc. (II) Collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Treasurer's records were held by the Rockefeller Foundation, because the RF Treasurer was also the Treasurer of the Davison Fund.
File Plan
Former Classification: IV 2B 08
Arrangement
As received.
Public welfare; Music; Missionaries; Medical care; Education; Charities; African Americans; Child welfare; Philanthropy; International relations; East Asia; Race and society; Urban policy; Westchester County (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Religion; Race relations; Public policy; Social problems; International cooperation; Quality of life; Hospitals; Davison Fund
- Certificate of Incorporation, By-Laws, and General Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Members of the Corporation - Minutes, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Board of Trustees - Minutes, 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Board of Trustees - Minutes, 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Committees - Executive Committee - Minutes, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Committees - Executive Committee - Minutes, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Committees - Finance Committee - Minutes, 1934-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Committees - Religious Projects Committee - Minutes, 1934-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Committees - Special Appropriations Committee - Minutes, 1934-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Treasurer's Office - Reports (with Affidavits and Abstractions), 1934-1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Documents of Reference - #1-130, 1935-1942 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Documents of Reference - #1-130, 1935-1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Appropriations and Resolutions, 1935-1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Appropriations and Resolutions, 1935-1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Funds (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Scope and Contents
  Principal Fund, 1934-1940; Surplus and Deficiency Fund, 1935-1937, 1941-1942
- Liquidation Reserve, 1939-1942; Salary Schedules, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Securities (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Socony-Vacuum Oil Company, Inc., 1934-1942 Standard Oil Company (NJ), 1934-1942 Proxies, 1934, 1939-1940
- Taxes (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Capital Stock (Fed.), 1935-1936 Federal Income, 1934-1942
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Analysis Journal, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Appropriations Ledger, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Cash Book, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Journal, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Ledger, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Securities Ledger, 1934-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Includes International Education Board, 1925-1931.
- Trial Balance, 1934-1941; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Vouchers, 1934-1937; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Vouchers, 1938-1942; Bound volume (Box 4, Folder 28)